Archit Guleria

Software Development Engineer II

Gurugram, India

+91 884 764 5367

architguleria280996@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/archit-guleria-379125126/

Summary

Software Engineer with 6 years of experience and a demonstrated history of working in the software industry. Well experienced in complex system design with an in-depth knowledge of various software design patterns and best in class implementation practices. Proficient in various technologies and skills like JAVA, AWS, Design patterns, DS/Algo, etc.

Work Experience

SDE II August, 2022 - present

Amazon

The application I work on is a Payment Instrument collection system for collecting employee details like bank accounts, card details etc.

The application also has other advanced features like Anytime Pay which allows users to be paid till a specific day of the month on request.

Following is a brief description of my work:

- 1. Designing highly scalable components capable of handling millions of requests easily. Implementing the backend for the BAC (Bank account collection) application with all the needed dashboards, metrics and alarms in place.
- 2. For each new country launch with a unique use case, understanding the requirements, doing the system design, implementing the functionality and then launching the system for the given country. Successfully did this for multiple countries.
- 3. Working with ML models to analyze data and get certain relevant information (Confidential).
- 4. Created and implemented the system design for depersonalization of terminated employee data from our system across all the launched countries. This is to meet country specific legal compliance like GDPR etc.

Senior Software Engineer Mphrx

January, 2020 - July, 2022

I worked in the product development team. The product was a hospital system used by various clients across the globe with features like online appointment, slot booking, tele-consultation, health record forms etc.

- 1. I worked on the system architecture design/improvements (eg migrating system code from Grails framework to Spring framework, introducing microservices architecture).
- 2. I took ownership of multiple system modules and ensured development to the best of standards. I was proactive in resolving bugs, production environment debugging and provided solutions at the earliest to prevent any impact on the client's business/workflow.
- 3. I also acted as a mentor for the junior developers, helped them with their learning as well as ensured their productivity.

Back End Developer Absolutdata Analytics

October, 2018 - January, 2020

Implementing various application backend components and designing the APIs. Providing innovative solutions to decrease manual work by automating it through code. Identifying various shortcomings in the project design and suggesting improvements. Writing high-quality code as per SonarQube standards along with unit test cases.

Software Developer - Intern Codroit Tech Pvt. Ltd.

June, 2018 - September, 2018

- Front end development using MaterialUI, ReactJs + redux and integrating with the backend APIs.
- Developing the backend APIs using Java in Spring Framework.

Full-stack Developer - Intern Smarter.Codes

January, 2017 - April, 2017

Working in AI projects making use of NLP and graph databases. Web Scraping - Extracting data from websites and storing it in the company servers. Querying DBpedia to extract data and store it in databases. Designing UI components as well as working on backend components.

Education

English

BTech in Computer Science and Engineering Punjab Engineering College (PEC)		August, 2014 - July, 2018
ligh School - 12th Class ISC Board Nount Carmel School		April, 2013 - April, 2014
Ion-medical - Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics		
High School - 10th Class ICSE board Mount Carmel School		April, 2011 - April, 2012
Skills		
Data Structures and Algorithms	Software Design Patterns	
System Design (HLD and LLD)	AWS - Components and Design	
Java, Typescript	Working with ML models	
 Working with Dependency Injection frameworks like Spring, Dagger, etc. 	 Using Sql/NoSql databases like DynamoDb, MongoDb, Cassandra, MySql, etc. 	

Hindi